<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Eric&#39;s Web.site</title>
    <link>https://ericsweb.site/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Eric&#39;s Web.site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ericsweb.site/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bearclaw. Cornstalk. Turtles. Get Yolked.</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/posts/bearclaw-cornstalk-turtles-getyolked/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/posts/bearclaw-cornstalk-turtles-getyolked/</guid>
      <description>What do these words mean?
I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I found them by accident, when poking around a part of the internet no one was ever supposed to find.
I was poking around my Pi-Hole (an ad-blocking/privacy solution), and noticed that one of the most blocked domains was ads.mopub.com. If you visit that URL, you will find that most enigmatic phrase: Bearclaw. Cornstalk. Turtles. Get Yolked., followed by a number between 1 and 1000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling Language Performance with Project Euler</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/posts/project-euler-performance-profiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/posts/project-euler-performance-profiling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been sitting on a side project for a while, working on it when I have time. The project in question is Project Euler - specifically, implementing Project Euler in a few different programming languages. Pretty soon after starting, I realized that I had an opportunity to compare the performance of these implementations across not only different programming languages, but also across different ways of running the code in question and optimizing it to not just reach the right answer, but to maximize performance in measurable ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Package Managers</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/posts/package-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/posts/package-managers/</guid>
      <description>From the time I first got Linux to boot on a laptop I had, I became entranced with the idea of a system package manager. From Wikipedia:
 A package manager or package management system is a collection of software tools that automates the process of installing, upgrading, configuring, and removing computer programs for a computer&amp;rsquo;s operating system in a consistent manner.
 Basically, a package manager lets you install software in a uniform way - on Ubuntu Linux, apt install 7zip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Purpose Computing – Then and Now</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2018/04/04/General-Purpose-Computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2018/04/04/General-Purpose-Computing/</guid>
      <description>The term &amp;ldquo;general purpose computing&amp;rdquo; is kind of a strange term. Until I was introduced to it within the context of computer science history, it didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense. I want to talk about the future and some interesting developments happening within the computer industry, but that&amp;rsquo;s really impossible without looking at how computers came to work like they do now.
Before General Purpose Computing # In the 1940s, computers were machines of war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Intel Disaster</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2018/01/04/Intel-Security-Bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2018/01/04/Intel-Security-Bug/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a hot topic right now, still in the early stages: one of the biggest security bugs ever.
Intel is a company that makes various components, but is most widely known for their processors for desktop and laptop computers. They are by far the largest processor manufacturer, with up to 70% market share, depending on your source. Processors power everything your computer does – in computer science 101, they&amp;rsquo;re called the main &amp;ldquo;brain&amp;rdquo; of the computer, which is fairly apt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Encryption Works</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/10/26/How-Encryption-Works/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/10/26/How-Encryption-Works/</guid>
      <description>These days, encryption is becoming more and more important to understand, politically and personally. However, when it gets discussed in an open forum, it&amp;rsquo;s usually discussed so abstractly that the layperson doesn&amp;rsquo;t really understand the specifics of what&amp;rsquo;s going on. That&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m here for. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about encryption in a way that anyone can understand, and explain how it works and why.
What is Encryption? # From Wikipedia: &amp;ldquo;encryption is the process of encoding a message or information in such a way that only authorized parties can access it&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Modern Video Works</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/08/27/how-video-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/08/27/how-video-works/</guid>
      <description>Video is one of the most important technologies on the internet today. We use it so much we don&amp;rsquo;t even really think about it anymore. We stream TV shows, watch cat videos, teleconference, and share on social media. It&amp;rsquo;s become common and mundane, but it took a lot of smart people working very hard to get to this point. Motion film is a bit over 100 years old, and in that time it&amp;rsquo;s gone from a strange novelty to a series of multibillion-dollar industries that we interact with every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/08/21/The-Problem-With-Powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/08/21/The-Problem-With-Powershell/</guid>
      <description>In my past life as a Windows/.NET developer, I spent a lot of time working with various parts of the .NET world, including PowerShell.
For those uninitiated, the .NET framework is the framework Microsoft has been increasingly pushing for development for their operating systems. Multiple programming languages in the MS world use this same framework - it&amp;rsquo;s made to work well across different programming languages. The most popular languages for the framework are C# (one of my favorite programming languages, right next to Swift), Visual C++, Visual Basic, F#, and PowerShell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Like FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/07/03/Why-I-Like-FreeBSD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/07/03/Why-I-Like-FreeBSD/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who know me may have noticed I&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about FreeBSD. When I get into a technology, I like to research it. I like to understand the philosophy behind it, and I like to learn how to use it to its full potential. When I&amp;rsquo;m into a technology, I try to dig in and maximize my use of it. So since I&amp;rsquo;ve been living with FreeBSD for quite a while, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain why I like it so much, and what it has to offer (in my opinion) over other alternatives, as well as reasons why I, personally, like it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case for the Artificial Sciences</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/06/09/The-Case-For-Artificial-Science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/06/09/The-Case-For-Artificial-Science/</guid>
      <description>The two traditional branches of science are the natural sciences (such as physics, chemistry, and biology) and the social sciences (such as sociology, psychology, and anthropology). Computer science falls into neither of these categories, as it is neither a study of the natural world nor a study of human society. It&amp;rsquo;s been argued that, because of this, the term &amp;ldquo;Computer Science&amp;rdquo; is a misnomer, instead relegating Computer Science to the realm of mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux and BSD - A Tale of Two Operating Systems</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/posts/adventures-in-bsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/posts/adventures-in-bsd/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using FreeBSD a lot recently. FreeBSD is similar to Linux operating systems in many ways, and at least initially, it will feel like home to Linux users. But along the way, there are lots of pitfalls stemming from the historical philosophical differences in the BSD and Linux communities. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about my adventures in BSDand Linux, coming from mainly a MacOS background with some experience in Linux operating systems and a soft spot for FreeBSD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Beamforming, and How Will it Change the World?</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/posts/beamforming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/posts/beamforming/</guid>
      <description>As the internet&amp;rsquo;s grown up, more and more areas have started to be explored, especially in consumer devices. The best examples are smarthome hardware, wearable tech, and the ever-growing power of smartphones. Engineers are moving Heaven and Earth to make everyday things slightly more convenient.
What is Beamforming? # It&amp;rsquo;s a wireless technology, based around electomagnetic fields, especially WiFi. Traditionally, WiFi is radiated out in a sphere, in the same way that light emits from a lightbulb in every direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Runs on Bad Code</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/posts/the-world-runs-on-bad-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/posts/the-world-runs-on-bad-code/</guid>
      <description>Code quality, the savior of, and the bane of, programmers.
Writing code is easy. I really do believe that with effort and willingness to learn, just about anybody can write a simple program. The challenge, however, is writing good code.
In the paraphrased words of Peter Welch (a lot of this post is inspired by his essay, Programming Sucks, and its counterpart by a different author, What Programming is Like), good code reads like poetry written by someone over thirty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Package Managers are Great - With a Focus on Homebrew</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/04/21/Package-Managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/04/21/Package-Managers/</guid>
      <description>I really like package managers. Often, I&amp;rsquo;ll even get a bit preachy about them. So guess what I&amp;rsquo;m going to do!
Package managers are a lovely piece of technology. Linux users will be very familiar with the terminology, but the fact is most of us interact with them regularly without even realizing it.
From Wikipedia: A package manager or package management system is a collection of software tools that automates the process of installing, upgrading, configuring, and removing computer programs for a computer&amp;rsquo;s operating system in a consistent manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem with File Systems</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/04/14/Filesystems-Suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/04/14/Filesystems-Suck/</guid>
      <description>File systems are organized hierarchically. This makes sense, and is somewhat intuitive to use. This is how your computer works. Everything is organized relative to the &amp;ldquo;root directory&amp;rdquo; (/ on Mac/Linux/BSD, C:\ on Windows). Every document, every executable, every system file is organized somewhere in that hierarchy. It&amp;rsquo;s how personal computers have worked for almost as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve had file systems on them. To those who are computer-savvy, or who grew up with computers, this makes complete sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today&#39;s Computers are Black Magic</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/04/08/Computers-Are-Black-Magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/04/08/Computers-Are-Black-Magic/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s computers are insanely fast and sophisticated. We don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily think of them that way, because they do such simple things like browse the web, read emails, and run dishwashers. Almost everything that uses electricity these days has a computer in it. We&amp;rsquo;re really seeing this with things like home automation, where even individual lightbulbs have small computers in them. They&amp;rsquo;re insanely cheap too, going to as little as $5 for something that can run a full operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethical Considerations in Advanced Robotics and AI</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/01/20/Ethical-Considerations-In-Advanced-Robotics-and-AI/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/01/20/Ethical-Considerations-In-Advanced-Robotics-and-AI/</guid>
      <description>Advanced robotics and Artificial Intelligence is a very new area of scientific and sociological discussion. There wind up being a lot of problems with these kinds of products as they become increasingly complex, and when something goes wrong it&amp;rsquo;s not always clear whether responsibility lies with the user or with the manufacturer. I was inspired by this article, where the author discussed
Important Terms # AI: Artificial Intelligence - A human-created entity that can respond to external stimuli in a way that is comparable to a human in terms of sophistication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
