<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on Eric&#39;s Web.site</title>
    <link>https://ericsweb.site/categories/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on Eric&#39;s Web.site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ericsweb.site/categories/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple&#39;s Gather Round - 12 September 2018</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2018/09/23/Gather-Round/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2018/09/23/Gather-Round/</guid>
      <description>Once again, I have to start out by commenting on how well-shot the opening sequence is. Great use of lighting and camera angles. Though it wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly funny or appropriate, it really is great from a technical standpoint to the point that even someone as pedestrian as me can see it.
iPhone # Three new models of iPhone were announced - the iPhone XS, XS Max, and XR. At least the silly tone of Apple&amp;rsquo;s opening video matches the silly naming of these phones - sounding like they&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be sports cars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple&#39;s WWDC - 4 June 2018</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2018/06/04/Apple-WWDC-4-June-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2018/06/04/Apple-WWDC-4-June-2018/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again – Apple&amp;rsquo;s World-Wide Developer Conference. The first day, June 4, Apple announces new software, and sometimes new hardware, that will be upcoming around Q3 of the year. I&amp;rsquo;m here to break down and summarize what they&amp;rsquo;re releasing and what I expect it to actually look like once it&amp;rsquo;s released. This year&amp;rsquo;s WWDC was expected to have less major changes than in the past, as Apple just made major hardware announcements and changes last year, as well as because this year (according to rumor) they&amp;rsquo;ve been largely focused on internal improvements in terms of performance and bugfixes over adding on new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Going on with Apple&#39;s Batteries?</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/12/29/Whats-Going-On-With-Apples-Batteries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/12/29/Whats-Going-On-With-Apples-Batteries/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;ve been various articles going around about Apple&amp;rsquo;s batteries in iPhones, or, specifically, Apple&amp;rsquo;s throttling of phones&amp;rsquo; hardware with older batteries. This post seeks to be primarily informational, but if you&amp;rsquo;re the owner of such a device that might be throttled, I&amp;rsquo;ll put in some useful information for you at the end of the post. But mostly, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be looking at the facts of the issue, since the internet in general and news in particular tends more towards sensationalism than complete information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Event 9/12/2017</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/09/14/Apple-Event-9-23-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/09/14/Apple-Event-9-23-2017/</guid>
      <description>Apple just did another event where they announced the iPhone 8 and iPhone X, among other things. Because I am as predictable as the flame wars about whether or not the event was any good, I&amp;rsquo;m here to give the highlights about the event so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to watch the whole 2-hour keynote.
Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk About iPhones # The next generation of iPhones is here, with the iPhone X and iPhone 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 MacBook Pro Review</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/06/17/2016-MacBook-Pro-Review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/06/17/2016-MacBook-Pro-Review/</guid>
      <description>Some Background # I have a bad habit of putting more background in these posts than I need to. So, if you want to know a bit more about the history of the product line, and the context of this review, read on. Otherwise, feel free to skip to the next section.
For my new job (I just graduated) as a professional software engineer, I got my hands on a 2016 MacBook Pro as my personal machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 WWDC Coverage</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/06/05/2017-WWDC-Coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/06/05/2017-WWDC-Coverage/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to write this, Apple&amp;rsquo;s 2017 World Wide Developer Conference keynote has just wrapped up. And what a big conference it was. Tim Cook said it was the biggest one they&amp;rsquo;ve ever done - and for once, that may not be hyperbole.
In science and engineering, there are two kinds of breakthroughs. The one we most often think of is the creation of new technology. And while that is certainly important, the advances that really change things are the ones that don&amp;rsquo;t bring about a new technology, but that make it accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 21 2017 Apple Press Release Coverage</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/03/23/Apple-Press-Release-Coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/03/23/Apple-Press-Release-Coverage/</guid>
      <description>Apple put out a press release on Monday, announcing a few minor new products. I&amp;rsquo;m here to cover what they did, and what I think of it. I&amp;rsquo;ll also say that I&amp;rsquo;m aggregating a lot from MacRumors, which is a website with Apple news and, in my opinion, is the fairest and has the highest journalistic integrity of the mainstream Apple news aggregators.
1. Now Lower-End iPad # Apple released a new lower-end iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple, Muster your Courage. It&#39;s time for USB-C.</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/03/16/iPad-USB-C/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/03/16/iPad-USB-C/</guid>
      <description>Apple, I&amp;rsquo;ve watched your progress over the last few years with interest. As a fan, follower, and analyst, I feel I need to call you out on it when you&amp;rsquo;re making a mistake.
And you&amp;rsquo;re making a mistake.
USB-C is the future. You know this. It&amp;rsquo;s why your new laptops have solely USB-C (and despite what the haters say, that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing). So it&amp;rsquo;s time to muster your famous courage, and follow through on that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Things I Like About Swift</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2017/02/23/3-Things-About-Swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2017/02/23/3-Things-About-Swift/</guid>
      <description>Within the past several months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a lot in Swift 3 and XCode 8. The language was a brand new experience for me, and there was quite a learning curve. I&amp;rsquo;ve never worked with a language like it and while, as always, programming skills carry over, the syntax of Swift proved tricky. However, after this time, I&amp;rsquo;ve either gained an appreciation for some of the more novel features in Swift, or else I&amp;rsquo;ve gained stockholm syndrome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 MacBook Pro Impressions</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2016/11/12/2016-Macbook-Pro-Impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2016/11/12/2016-Macbook-Pro-Impressions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction # Now that I actually have some time on my hands, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about Apple&amp;rsquo;s MacBook Pro line refresh. This refresh has long been asked for in Apple circles, after the line has gone stale. It seems to me that Apple has largely transitioned away from its computer line, treating them more as accessories to iPhone devices than as standalone products. It seems to me that the new iterations of MacBooks are largely informed by this philosophy, in that they&amp;rsquo;re coming in with lower power requirements, a smaller footprint, and longer battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dramatic Re-enactment of the iPhone 7&#39;s Development Pitch</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/posts/iphone-7s-development-pitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/posts/iphone-7s-development-pitch/</guid>
      <description>T is Tim Cook. All others&amp;rsquo; positions are inferred by context. This is just a fun little script I wrote.
T: &amp;ldquo;We need better photo quality.&amp;rdquo;
A: &amp;ldquo;Really? I think users care more about-&amp;rdquo;
The sniper Apple keeps across the street to monitor its engineers takes out A.
B: &amp;ldquo;Photo quality is my top priority!&amp;rdquo;
T: &amp;ldquo;Okay, good. What can we do about it?&amp;rdquo;
B: &amp;ldquo;Well, people like zooming in, but digital zoom sucks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09/07 Apple Event Coverage</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2016/09/10/0907-Apple-Event-Coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2016/09/10/0907-Apple-Event-Coverage/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;ll do my regular coverage of the Apple event now that I&amp;rsquo;ve sat on it a few days, broken into relevant subsections:
Apple Watch: # Added a new iteration, called &amp;ldquo;Series 2&amp;rdquo;, and one that&amp;rsquo;s basically the same but with a processor update, &amp;ldquo;Series 1&amp;rdquo;. Processor update to both. Nothing truly substantial, but it will help future-proof it. Series 2 is waterproof and has built-in GPS. This makes it more usable for fitness without an iPhone nearby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Apple&#39;s Review Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://ericsweb.site/2015/09/23/Excerpts-from-Apple&#39;s-Review-Guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericsweb.site/2015/09/23/Excerpts-from-Apple&#39;s-Review-Guidelines/</guid>
      <description>From this document: https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/
&amp;ldquo;…if your app is plain creepy, it may not be accepted&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;We have lots of serious developers who don&amp;rsquo;t want their quality Apps to be surrounded by amateur hour.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;We will reject Apps for any content or behavior that we believe is over the line. What line, you ask? Well, as a Supreme Court Justice once said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll know it when I see it&amp;rdquo;.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;If you run to the press and trash us, it never helps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
